taxjar.com 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy - TaxJar

Thank you for visiting the TPS Unlimited, Inc. d/b/a TaxJar (“TaxJar”, “us”, “we”, “our”) website and reviewing our privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy”). This privacy policy explains the types of personal information (“Personal Data”) we may collect from and about you, as well as how we may disclose, use and protect that information.

This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect about visitors to the TaxJar website (the “Site”) and TaxJar’s [state sales tax preparation and submission services] (the “Services”). This Privacy Policy applies both to current and former customers of TaxJar as well as to those visitors to the TaxJar website who do not become customers of TaxJar.

### Information Collection

Personal Data That You Provide Through The Services: When you visit the Site or use the Services, we may collect Personal Data about you when you voluntarily provide such information, including from the following categories and sources:

  * Information we receive when you create an account or request services or information from us or companies with whom we have business relationships, or when you complete surveys or polls, such as your name, address, e-mail address and payment or billing information.
  * Information to prepare your sales tax return.
  * Information we collect via APIs which include your transaction history.
  * Information we receive when providing technical or customer support for you.

**The website is operated in the United States of America (U.S.) and is only intended for use by individuals accessing it from the U.S. If you are located in another jurisdiction, then please be aware that any Personal Data you elect to supply will be transferred from your current location to the U.S. to our servers, offices or and/or to the third parties mentioned in the circumstances described below, and be subject to U.S. laws regarding data privacy and collection, which may be less stringent than or otherwise different from the laws in effect in the country in which you are located. By using this website or by voluntarily providing us with your Personal Data, you acknowledge and agree with your Personal Data being processed and transferred as described above.**

In order to prepare your relevant sales tax return documentation and history, we collect information about you, such as your name, address, and tax identification number, business information as well as your online transaction history and sales taxes collected, your total previous tax payments, and other information. Collectively, this information is known as “Sales Tax Information”.

### Cookie Policy | Other Information

Non-Identifiable Data: When you interact with TaxJar through the Site or Services, we receive and store certain personally non-identifiable information. Such information, which is collected passively using various technologies, cannot presently be used to specifically identify you. TaxJar may store such information itself or such information may be included in databases owned and maintained by TaxJar affiliates, agents or service providers. The Services may use such information and pool it with other information to track, for example, the total number of visitors to our Site, the number of visitors to each page of our Site, and the domain names of our visitors' Internet service providers. It is important to note that no Personal Data is available or used in this process.

We may also collect information through the use of a software technology called “cookies.” Internet cookies allow us to customize our website for you by placing small files on your computer as you visit various components of the Site. Through the use of cookies, we can display only those items that may be of interest to you on a particular site, or make it easier for you to access your account information. Information we collect through Internet cookies does not identify you personally. You can choose to decline cookies while at our website, however, this may limit your ability to access certain areas of the website. Most browsers accept and maintain cookies by default. Check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preference.

We also may employ a software technology called beacons or tracking pixels that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective and which pages visitors view. These pixels are a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. Like cookies, these pixels are not tied to users’ personally identifiable information.

Like most standard website servers, we use log files. Information collected in log files may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks. We utilize this information to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. This information is not personally identifiable.

Advertising networks that serve ads on our website may assign a different cookie to you. The information collected is anonymous and is not linked to your personal information. These cookies may be used to select which ads you see and determine the effectiveness of this advertising. You may choose to decline cookies from third-party ad servers, which TaxJar does not control.

Aggregated Personal Data: In an ongoing effort to better understand and serve our users, TaxJar often conducts research on its customer demographics, interests and behavior based on the Personal Data and other information provided to us. This research may be compiled and analyzed on an aggregate basis, and TaxJar may share this aggregate data with its affiliates, agents and business partners. This aggregate information does not identify you personally. TaxJar may also disclose aggregated user statistics in order to describe our services to current and prospective business partners, and to other third parties for other lawful purposes.

Analytics and Do Not Track Signals: We may (and we may allow third party service providers to) use cookies or other technologies to collect information about your browsing activities over time and across different websites following your use of the Services. For example, we use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to help us analyze how users use the Site and enhance your experience when you use the Service. For more information on how Google uses this data, go to www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/.

Our Service currently does not respond to “Do Not Track” (DNT) signals and operates as described in this Privacy Policy whether or not a DNT signal is received. If we do so in the future, we will describe how we do so in this Privacy Policy.

### Information Use

TaxJar uses the Personal Data you provide in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. If you provide Personal Data for a certain reason, we may use the Personal Data in connection with the reason for which it was provided. For instance, if you contact us by email, we will use the Personal Data you provide to answer your question or resolve your problem. Also, if you provide Personal Data in order to obtain access to our Services, we will use your Personal Data to provide you with access to such Services and to monitor your use of such Services. We use your Sales Tax Information to prepare and present your sales tax summary, and to provide related assistance and services. TaxJar and its subsidiaries and affiliates (the “Related Companies”) may also use your Personal Data and other personally non-identifiable information collected to help us improve the content and functionality of our services, to better understand our users and to improve the our services. TaxJar and its affiliates may use this information to contact you in the future to tell you about services we believe will be of interest to you. If we do so, each marketing communication we send you will contain instructions permitting you to "opt-out" of receiving future marketing communications.

We offer various Internet Chat services, for example, to speak with a support representative. Internet Chat transmissions are encrypted but you should not supply more personal or tax information than is required to address your specific issue A transcript of the session is generated and retained, and may be used to resolve current and potential future questions or issues.

We retain history of your transactions. This information may also be used to provide you with a copy of your sales tax history for your convenience.

If TaxJar intends on using any Personal Data in any manner that is not consistent with this Privacy Policy, you will be informed of such anticipated use prior to or at the time at which the Personal Data is collected.

### Our Disclosure of Your Personal Data and Other Information

TaxJar is not in the business of selling your personal or tax return information to anyone. There are, however, certain circumstances in which we may share your Personal Data with certain third parties without further notice to you, as set forth below and in the section above:

We may use service companies on our behalf to perform certain business-related functions. Examples of such functions include mailing information, maintaining databases and processing payments. When we employ another entity to perform a function of this nature, we only provide them with the information that they need to perform their specific function.

We may disclose your name or testimonials that you provide for advertising or marketing purposes.

We may disclose your information to affiliates or non-affiliated third parties when we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is required by law. This may occur in connection with a court order, legal process, or other judicial, administrative or investigative proceeding that produces a request for information from TaxJar.

Should we sell, merge or transfer any part of our business, part of that sale may include your personal information. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, Personal Data may be part of the transferred assets.

### Collection and use of Children’s Personal Information

Because of the financial nature of the services we provide, we do not market our website to children under the age of 13, nor do we knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13.

### Third Party Services

In connection with the promotion or your use of the Services, the Services may enable linking with various third-party services and products (“Third Party Services”). These Third Party Services may include tax return preparation, refund processing, professional tax review and audit defense, among others. If you decide to use Third Party Services, you are responsible for reviewing and understanding the terms and conditions governing any Third Party Services.

When you add a Third Party Service account to the Service, we will collect relevant information necessary to enable the Service to access that Third Party Services and your data contained within that Third Party Service. As part of such integration, the Third Party Service will provide us with access to certain information that you have provided to Third Party Service, and we will use, store and disclose such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. However, please remember that the manner in which Third-Party Services use, store and disclose your information is governed solely by the policies of such third parties. You agree that the third-party provider, and not TaxJar, is solely responsible for the performance of the Third Party Services.

### Your Choices

You can visit certain portions of the Site without providing any Personal Data. If you choose not to provide any Personal Data, you may not be able to use certain of the Services.

### Exclusions

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any Personal Data collected by TaxJar other than Personal Data collected through the Services. This Privacy Policy shall not apply to any unsolicited information you provide to TaxJar through our Services or through any other means. This includes, but is not limited to, information posted to any public areas of ourSservices, such as forums, any ideas for new products or modifications to existing products, and other unsolicited submissions (collectively, “Unsolicited Information”). All Unsolicited Information shall be deemed to be non-confidential and TaxJar shall be free to reproduce, use, disclose, and distribute such Unsolicited Information to others without limitation or attribution.

### Security

TaxJar takes reasonable steps to protect the Personal Data provided via our services from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. However, no Internet or email transmission is ever fully secure or error free. In particular, email sent to or from our services may not be secure. Therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via email. Please keep this in mind when disclosing any Personal Data to TaxJar via the Internet.

### Other Terms and Conditions

Your access to and use of our services is subject to the License Agreement for TaxJar Software and Services at https://www.taxjar.com/terms-of-service/.

### Changes to our Privacy Statement

If we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, including a material change in the way we use any personal information collected on www.TaxJar.com, we will notify you by using one of the following methods at least thirty (30) days prior to the effective date of such change: (1) we will post a notice on our website describing the change; or (2) we will send you electronic mail notifying you of the change. Your continued use of the Site or Services after such effective date shall indicate your agreement with the terms of such revised Privacy Policy.

### Communication with us about Privacy

If you have privacy-related questions that are not addressed here, please contact the Privacy Team via email at privacy@taxjar.com.
